hi this is AJ Hogue
director of the Effortless English Club
welcome to our new set of lessons
these are called the Power English lessons
the reason they're called Power English is because
in these lessons we're going to do two things
No.1 you're going to learn English of course as always
we have the mini stories
which are our favourite lessons for most of our members
uh but the content the uh
the focus the topics in these lessons
are gonna be focused on the psychology of learning
and the psychology of success
now these ideas they're not just my ideas
in fact they come from a lot of other people
they come from people like Tony Robbins
who's a famous success coach
um Robert Anton Wilson
Joe Vitale Robert Kiyosaki Alan Watts so
I've taken a lot of ideas from a lot of different people
about this this topic of the psychology of success
and the reason that we're going to talk about this
in these lessons is that in my experience
most English students struggle and fail because of psychology
not because of methods not because of teachers
those things are important
but uh you know Tony Robbins talks about uh
the fact that psychology is 80% of success
and I think he's right based on my experience with uh
many many English students
psychology is 80% of success
so 20% are the methods you use to study
twenty percent are are the schools you go to
the teachers you have the books you use those are important
we talk a lot about them, but the other 80% is psychology
your motivation your emotions
how you manage your time
all of these things are in fact much
much more important what I saw in my classes
were that the enthusiastic students
the energetic students
the optimistic students always Learned much faster
they succeeded the ones who failed
the ones who dropped out and quit
the ones who struggled had the opposite mentality
they had a very negative mentality
their motivation was low they tended to be pessimistic
they felt that they weren't good at English
they had ideas that English was very tough
very difficult they struggled there
they didn't have enthusiasm for English they didn't love English
so in these lessons we're gonna talk about
how can you manage your emotions
how can you develop that strong
powerful enthusiastic attitude towards English
how can you maintain it so that you don't get bored
so then in fact
you get stronger and stronger with English
and your psychology gets stronger and you succeed
you reach your goals
you speak fluently effortlessly so among uh teachers
English teachers language teachers
uh this topic is called non linguistic factors
non linguistic factors so
what non linguistic factors means
is things that are not related to language learning directly
when we talk about language learning research
when we talk about the
the best methods to use when you learn English
those are linguistic factors right
they're related to the language
non linguistic factors means not related to the language
this has nothing to do with English
it's more about psychology motivation
for example is a non linguistic factor
so that all it really means is just emotional factors
and there are actually many
research studies about this topic
Doctor Stephen Crashin down in Los Angeles
probably again the expert in language acquisition
language learning has done many studies
and he has also looked at many studies
and he's found that non linguistic factors are equally
or in fact more important than the linguistic factors
to determine who is successful ultimately
what that means is that things like your emotions
things like the your peer group
the community that you belong to
your feelings about English are as important or more important
than the methods you're using to learn English
so how we gonna do this how we gonna learn
well one of the things we have to do is create a daily English ritual
you need to engage your physiology
that means you need to engage and use your body
you need to engage and use your subconscious
that's how you start to affect and strengthen
your psychology
so we have to strengthen our psychology
what does that mean really it means
affecting your body and your mind at the same time
so that you actually feel better
your emotions are happier while you're learning English
and I know this is the opposite of what you Learned in school
you probably didn't feel very happy
when you were sitting in your English classes
but when you're learning with effortless English
it's very important for you to feel happy
for your body to feel good for your mind to feel good
for you to emotionally enjoy the process of learning English
of course it's just more fun
you're gonna like it a lot better but uh
the other benefit is that you actually will learn faster
you'll improve your grammar faster
you'll improve your pronunciation faster
you'll remember vocabulary words better
longer and faster when you feel good
so there's a very practical reason for doing this too
so we're gonna talk a lot in detail in these lessons about how to do this
but just right now during this introduction
let's talk a little bit about a daily plan
something you could do immediately right now
today to start improving your success with English
by changing your psychology
so here's a little ritual a little plan
you can follow every day to start improving
to start feeling better
and therefore improve your motivation
and to learn English faster and faster and faster
better and better and better and it's very simple
so the first thing you're gonna do is
when you get up in the morning
the first part of this plan this daily plan
you wanna get into a peak emotional state
peak means top for example uh
the top of a mountain we talk about a top of a mountain
the very top we call the peak
so we're saying a peak emotional state means
a top emotional state
or top emotional feeling means you wanna feel great
not just good you wanna feel really great
it's the first thing you need to do before you
listen to any English lessons before you study
you wanna first be sure that you feel great how can you do it
well it's really easy uh I recommend
uh for example using music
and I actually do this myself in the morning
most mornings I will uh
put on some great exciting music that I love
jump around act like a crazy person
and get myself feeling energetic and happy
do that first before you listen
so move your body smile we're gonna talk
about this  more in detail in later lessons
but just for now every morning when you get up first
put on some music some energetic
happy music that you like smile move around
do that for maybe five minutes
maybe 10 minutes then when you're feeling really great
your body's moving you feel like you have energy
you're happy then start your English lessons
the first thing you want to listen to is the main article
the main audio that's how you're gonna use these lessons
so the first thing is listen to the main talk
and you can read this as well the first time
if you cannot understand easily
you can read the transcript and listen at the same time
do this perhaps two times a day
starting with the main story and reading
use a dictionary if you need to to look up new words
next listen to the vocabulary so in the vocabulary again
I will discuss the meanings of some of
the difficult words that I used
and again you can read the transcript of that vocabulary lesson
there's always a transcript you can read
if you can't understand my speaking
if I'm too fast
then read at the same time it's okay
next you'll listen to the mini story
and the mini story is the most important lesson
the mini story is designed for deep learning
in the mini story I'm going to ask a lot of very easy questions
while I tell a story in fact
I really ask the story I don't tell the story
why am I doing this students ask me
why are the questions so easy
well the questions are supposed to be easy
because I want you to answer fast and automatically
I want you to train your brain
teach your brain to answer very quickly
I don't want you to translate from your language
to English or from English to your language
it's a bad habit it'll make you speak very slowly
I want you to just answer quickly automatically very fast
so that's why I ask so many questions
like questions again again again again again
very easy your job answer the questions quickly
you can answer with only one or two words
it's okay short answers are fine
you don't need to answer with a big long sentence
in fact short is better
so that's the uh the order that you're going to follow
you're gonna listen to the main article first
one or two times you can read as well if you need to
then you're going to listen to the vocabulary
one or two times each day
and then finally you're gonna listen to the mini story
one or two times or more
you can also read the transcript for the mini story in the beginning
now another important point when you're
listening to these lessons do not study them
don't struggle to memorize just relax and listen
if necessary you can read as well as I said if you need to but relax
you're not trying to memorize anything just let it come in
let the English come into your ears and into your eyes
don't think about it don't analyze it
do not think about grammar
the mini stories will help you learn grammar subconsciously
so don't don't interrupt that process by trying to analyze it
don't think about grammar rules you want to learn like a native speaker
and that means you're going to learn the patterns
of English in these many stories
you might not be able to explain them
just like native speakers
usually cannot explain grammar rules
but that's okay you wanna be able to use them correctly
that's the important part so again
you wanna relax do not study
do not think about grammar rules
do not try to translate just relax and listen
that's why we call it effortless English
it should be effortless you should be smiling
relaxed and just listening
another important point you want to move your body
while you're listening to the lessons
this will keep your energy high
so what do I mean by that
well a really easy way to do this is just to walk
you got an iPod you got the your earphones in
listen to the lessons while you go for a walk
you can do two things at one time you exercise
you improve your body and you listen to English lessons
and improve your mind at the same time
uh if you're sitting in a train
then maybe you just stretch your body a little bit
if you're in your car you can move a little bit
you can move around in your seat
if you're at your house you can go crazy
you can jump around you can exercise very strongly
you can go to the gym
do something with your body
while you're listening to the lessons
it will keep your energy high
it will keep you feeling better
you'll actually learn faster by doing that
and finally a very very important point
you need to use our deep learning method
that means you listen to each lesson set
for one week or more so for example
this introduction it's got three parts
there's a a main lecture a main talk
there's a vocabulary section and there's a mini story
well those three you wanna listen to those three everyday
for seven days
you want that repetition repetition is very important
you wanted to go deeply into your brain
just one time is not enough
even if it's very easy for you
if you listen you understand everything
it's simple still follow the deep learning method
still listen to the whole set for one week or more
on the other hand if it seems very difficult
listen longer two weeks is okay
doesn't matter the point is
you want it to go very deeply into your brain
which means you want it to be almost um effortless
it's just gonna go into your brain
and eventually just come out without you thinking
and that requires deep learning requires a lot of repetition
so, that's kind of your basic plan for using these lessons
again first you're gonna get into a peak state
you're gonna get excited
you're gonna jump around you're gonna listen to music
you're gonna feel great
then you're going to listen to the the main lecture
the main audio one or two times
then you're gonna listen to the vocabulary
one or two times
then you're going to listen to the mini story one two three
four five times every day and remember relax
feel good and enjoy the lessons while you listen
okay that is it for our main section for this uh
introduction next is the vocabulary
I'll see you next time bye bye