hello welcome to the vocabulary
for the introduction to power lessonsو let's start
okay let's talk about our first word is linguistic
linguistic means related to language or about language
it's an adjective so linguistic factors
I mention linguistic factors
a factor is an element for example it's a piece of something
so linguistic factors means elements about language
elements related to language
or even more simply things, things related to language
and then in this talk I talk about non linguistic factors
of course non means not it's negative
so, non linguistic factors means things not about language
things not related to language
so in the talk I'm talking about for example two different things
1 are emotional factors emotional elements,emotional things
and then the other is linguistic factors
so for example study method, that's a linguistic factor
it's connected to language learning very directly
it's a linguistic factor it's a language related thing
on the other hand emotion is not directly related
is not directly connected to language learning
makes most people don't think so, so it's a non linguistic factor
alright great, so that's linguistic and factor
let's talk about next subconscious
I mention the word subconscious
sometimes you hear the word unconscious is another uh
synonym for that but subconscious means something
that is under your normal thinking
so for example if you're quite hungry
suddenly you find that you're hungry but you're busy
you're thinking about something else
you're reading a book
but kind of under your thinking you have this idea
I'm hungry I'm hungry
I'm hungry it's not a conscious thought
it's not a strong direct thought
it's not at the top of your brain
he sub means under or below, so it's kind of in the bottom
the back of your brain
this sort of quiet small voice or this quiet small um
thought so that subconscious
so I mention that you want to engage your subconscious
to engage means uh to use, to use or to like turn on
so to turn on your subconscious
to use your subconscious to engage your subconscious
it means you want to use those
emotions that are in the back of your brain
or the bottom of your brain
you want to use that quiet voice you want to use those
strong emotions that are kind of in the back
because they're very powerful
so engage your subconscious means use those means
choose to use them in a powerful way
I also talk about engaging your physiology physiology
physiology means related to the body
it's related to the word physical physical means body
something that is connected to your body or in your body
and not your brain not your mind
it's body and physiology again is a similar idea
physiology means uh what is happening in your body
it's the systems in your body
it's the parts of your body so again
physio engage your physiology means use your body right
engage just turn on or use physiology body
so engage your physiology
engage your body use the parts of your body
use the systems in your body
that's what that means alright
great next uh, let's talk about the word peak
so peak I mentioned in the main story peak means top
now often we use this to describe for exampleing mountain
the very top of a mountain we say it's the peak
the mountain peak the peak of the mountain the very top part
we also use it in the phrase peak performance
or performance means performing or doing something
peak means top so it means doing something in a top way
in the very best way
sometimes we use this with sports
so he is a peak performance athlete
he's a top performing athlete
he's the very best performing athlete
so that's again peak meaning top, very top or sometimes meaning best
okay so peak meaning top so emotional state
I talk about peak emotional state
so top or best peak emotional, of course feelings and state
state means um kind of your situation or experience
so an emotional state means
it's the general emotional feeling you have right now
so I might say I'm in an angry emotional state
that means it's kind of a long term idea
means generally for some time I feel angry
this is a very formal kind of academic or intellectual way to say I'm angry
okay, so this is a little bit more formal kind of English
but again an emotional state
it's a it's a general emotional feeling
and it has a little bit of the idea of a long time
so a peak emotional state a top or best emotional state
it means feeling very good for a while
right, say I'm in a peak emotional state
I'm feeling very good for some time
okay now, that is the vocabulary lesson
for the introduction to power
of course if there are other words you did not understand
you can use the text
use the transcript and a dictionary and you know
just find the word in your dictionary and write it on the text
and you can learn more vocabulary that way
it's very difficult for me to guess exactly which words
you know and which words you don't know
because every student is different
so I will cover some of the main words
the words I think are quite important
but if there are other words you don't know
just use the text and a dictionary
and write the meaning on the text it's fine
okay I will see you next for the mini story
thanks and see you again soon