hi this is AJ Hug, welcome to the mini story
for introduction to Power English
let's get started in the mini story
I will tell a kind of strange funny stupid story
uh usually actually I will ask
the story means I will ask a lot of questions
the reason I ask these questions is to get a lot of repetition
so that the grammar structure
the grammar pattern will go into your brain deeply
because you're getting again and again and again
you don't need to think about it
just relax listen to the story
answer the questions quickly
if you need to you can pause your iPod
pause your computer and answer the questions
or if it's too fast just listen
you don't have to speak speaking is optional
you can do it if you want to answer the questions
great shout them out
if you don't if it's too difficult
or you're in a train with other people
it's fine just listen and relax
it's okay too okay let's start
there was a beautiful woman named Sophie
Sophie had to play Tiger Woods in golf
in just one month
who had to play Tiger Woods in golf in just one month
well Sophie
Sophie
had to play Tiger Woods in golf in just one month
what kind of woman was Sophie?
Sophie was a beautiful woman
who did she have to play?
Tiger Woods she had to play Tiger Woods
who had to play Tiger Woods?
Sophie Sophie had to play Tiger Woods in tennis right?
no no
no not in tennis
in golf Sophie had to play Tiger Woods in golf
when did Sophie have to play Tiger Woods in golf?
in one month Sophie had to play Tiger Woods in golf
in just one month
was Sophie worried or was Sophie happy?
Sophie was worried
why was she worried?
well, because Tiger Woods is the No. 1 golfer in the world
and Sophie was not good
was Sophie a good golfer?
no Sophie was a terrible golfer in fact
was Tiger Woods a good golfer?
well yes, of course Tiger Woods was a great golfer
and he still is a great golfer
so Sophie went to Japan
where did she go?
Japan Sophie went to Japan
who went to Japan?
that's right Sophie. Sophie went to Japan
why did she go to Japan?
well to find a golf coach
of course, she went to Japan to find a golf coach
where did she go to find a golf coach?
to Japan she went to Japan to find a golf coach
to find what?
a golf coach, she went to Japan to find a golf coach
she found the coach named Yoda
what was the coach's name?
Yoda, the coach's name was Yoda
was the coach's name Bob?
no, the coach's name was not Bob
the coach's name was Yoda
whose name was Yoda?
well, the coach's name was Yoda
what was Yoda?
Yoda was a golf coach
he said I can help you learn golf Sophie
he said if you use your subconscious
you will become a golf master
what did Yoda say?
he said if you use your subconscious
you will become a golf master
what did Sophie need to use?
her subconscious
Yoda said if you use your subconscious
you will become a golf master
so if she used her subconscious. what would she become?
a golf master he said
if you use your subconscious
you'll become a golf master
would she become a tennis master?
or would she become a golf master?
if she used her subconscious.
well if she used her subconscious
of course, she would become a golf master
what did she have to use?
her subconscious, she had to use her subconscious
to become a golf master
who said this to Sophie?
Yoda Yoda said this to Sophie
what did he say?
he said if you use your subconscious
you will become a golf master
so Sophie tried to use her subconscious
she closed her eyes every time she played golf
Yoda said use your subconscious, close your eyes
unfortunately it didn't work
did Sophie become a golf master?
no she didn't
she did not every time she hit the ball
it went into the trees
did Sophie try to use her subconscious?
yes she did, she tried to use her subconscious
she closed her eyes and tried to use her subconscious
when she tried to use her subconscious?
was she successful?
no she wasn't, she was not successful
when she tried to use her subconscious
every time she hit the ball
it went into the woods into the trees
poor Sophie, so Sophie went to Hawaii
who went to Hawaii? Yoda?
not Yoda, Sophie, Sophie went to Hawaii
why did she go to Hawaii?
to find another golf coach
why did she go?
did Tiger Woods go to Hawaii?
no, no, no Tiger Woods didn't go to Hawaii
where did Tiger Woods go?
South Carolina, Tiger Woods went to South Carolina
where did Sophie go?
she went to Hawaii
why did Tiger Woods go to South Carolina?
well to find a coach, he also wanted a golf coach
he found an army golf coach
the army golf coach said
you must run 30 miles every day
did Tiger Woods close his eyes when he played golf?
no, no, no he didn't try to use his subconscious
Tiger Woods ran 30 miles every day
he did not try to use his subconscious
Sophie had tried to use her subconscious
Tiger Woods did not
so Sophie went to Hawaii
and she found a surfing golf coach named Farley
what kind of golf coach did she find?
a surfing golf coach
who found a surfing golf coach?
Sophie, Sophie found a surfing golf coach
he said if you practice and surf every day
you will always succeed
what did she have to do?
she had to practice golf while surfing
did she have to practice golf and surfing?
at the same time or at different times?
at the same time, she had to practice golf while surfing
at the same time as surfing
so she got on the surfboard, she was surfing
and she was trying to play golf at the same time
who was trying to practice golf while surfing?
Tiger Woods?
no not Tiger Woods, Sophie
Sophie was trying to surf while playing golf
she was trying to play golf while surfing
was she successful?
no unfortunately not she got very wet
but she did not improve
was Sophie successful practicing golf and surfing?
no she wasn't, she fell into the water every time
every time she got wet
she was still a terrible golfer
was Tiger Woods still a terrible golfer?
no of course not
Tiger Woods was still a great golfer
the best golfer, so who was still a terrible golfer?
Sophie, Sophie was still a terrible golfer
she had tried to use her subconscious and she failed
she had tried to surf and play golf and she had failed
now she was very worried
only one more week to play Tiger Woods
she went to San Diego, why did she go to San Diego?
well of course
she went to San Diego to find another golf coach
why did she go?
to find another golf coach she went to Tony Robbins
who was Tony Robbins?
Tony Robbins was a peak performance coach
was he a peak performance coach?
or did he teach people to do things badly?
of course he was a peak performance coach
he taught people to do things very well
who was a peak performance coach?
Tony Robbins Tony Robbins was a peak performance coach
was Sophie a peak performance coach?
no she wasn't
Sophie was a terrible golfer
Tony Robbins was a peak performance coach
Sophie said help me Tony help me
Tony said, if you engage your physiology you will be a master
what did he say?
he said if you engage your physiology
you will be a master
did Tony want her to use her mind? her brain?
no, no, no he said, if you engage your physiology
you will be a master your body
did he want her to use her body very well?
or did he want her to use her mind her brain very well?
he wanted her to use her body
her physiology he said, if you engage your physiology
if you use your body, you will be a master
who wanted Sophie to engage her physiology?
Tony Robbins wanted Sophie to engage her physiology
Tony Robbins wanted Sophie to use her body correctly
in a peak performance way
Tony taught her to get into a peak state
did he teach her to feel bad?
no, no, no he taught her the opposite
he taught her to get into a peak emotional state
he taught her to feel really great
was she in a peak emotional state or a bad emotional state?
she was in a peak emotional state
a top emotional state she felt top great wonderful best
who was in a peak emotional state?
Sophie Sophie was in a peak emotional state
then Tony said, now practice golf
did Sophie practice golf while she was in a peak emotional state?
yes exactly, Sophie practice golf
while she was in a peak emotional state
did she practice golf
at the same time that she was in a peak emotional state?
yes at the same time
she practice golf while she was in a peak emotional state
she improved very quickly
finally, the day came
Sophie played Tiger Woods
Tiger was very tired he looked very tired
but Sophie was in a peak emotional state
during the whole game
finally at the end of the game
Sophie won she beat Tiger Woods
Tiger cried, Sophie you're the best now
he wrote a check to Sophie for $85 million
how much money did Tiger give Sophie?
$85 million he wrote a check for $85 million
he gave Sophie $85 million
how much did Sophie earn?
she earned $85 million
did Tiger Woods earn $85 million or lose $85 million?
Tiger lost $85 million
was Tiger happy?
no he wasn't, Tiger cried and cried he was very sad
was Tiger in a peak emotional state?
no Tiger was in a terrible emotional state
he was sad he was depressed
he was in a very bad emotional state
how about Sophie?
was Sophie in a great top peak emotional state
oh yeah she was in a top
great fantastic peak emotional state
she was happy she was excited and now she was rich
okay that is the end of the mini story
for the introduction to Power English
again listen to this mini story once or twice every day
for seven days or more
the questions the repetition
will help you effortlessly learn the vocabulary
and you'll be learning grammar too
it's kind of a secret grammar method
don't think about the grammar
please do not think about it
just relax, listen to the questions answer the questions
and every day
you'll start to learn these basic patterns of English
again and again and again more deeply each day
so again, listen to this lesson every day for 7 days or more
if you get bored move your body
jump up and down feel better and then start again
okay I will see you next time bye bye